A Register of the Stephen J. Tonsor Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-1999 and undated. (Box 30)
  - "Cracks in the Kremlin Wall,", undated. (Folder 31: 20)
    Holograph. Includes clippings, 1988 April 2
  - "Crisis of Historicism,", undated. (Folder 31: 21)
    Holograph outline. Includes printed matter
  - "Crisis, Reform and Restoration,", undated. (Folder 31: 22)
  - "Decadence and the Machine,", undated. (Folder 31: 23)
  - "Decadence and the Machine II,", undated. (Folder 31: 24)
  - "Decadence, Past and Present,", undated. (Folder 31: 25)
    Holograph. Includes notes and bibliography
  - "In Defense of Aristocracy,", undated. (Folder 31: 26)
  - "Destiny's Opportunist," review of Robert Shobel, Coolidge: An American Enigma, undated. (Folder 31: 27)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes printed matter
  - "Developments in Modern Philosophy,", undated. (Box-folder 32: 1)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes background materials and notes
  - "The Dilemmas of Unification,", undated. (Folder 32: 2)
    Holograph. Includes clippings, notes, and outline
  - "The Door in the Wall: The Garden and the Journey,", undated. (Folder 32: 3)
  - "Dorothy Day and the Catholic Worker Movement,", undated. (Folder 32: 4)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes related materials
  - "Early Christianity and the Problem of Equality,", undated. (Folder 32: 5)
  - "Earthly Bliss as a Substitute for Beatific Vision,", undated. (Folder 32: 6)
  - "Ecumenical History in the Current Climate of Opinion,", undated. (Folder 32: 7)
    Holograph. Includes outline, printed matter, and fragment
  - "Edmund Burke and the Principles of Revolutionary Development," and "The Sublime,", undated. (Folder 32: 8)
    Holograph. Includes notes and printed matter
  - "Education in the 1970's: Consolidation and Reform,", undated. (Folder 32: 9)
  - "Eighteenth Century Historical Thought,", undated. (Folder 32: 10)
    Holograph. Includes holograph notes by an unidentified individual
  - "Elites, Community and the Truth: A Little Story,", undated. (Folder 32: 11)
  - "Eos and Romanticism: A Study in the Transmission of Ideas,", undated. (Folder 32: 12)
  - "Equality and Ancient Society: The Egyptian Instance,", undated. (Folder 32: 13)
  - "Equality as a Factor in the American and French Revolutions,", undated. (Folder 32: 14)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes holograph note
  - "Equality in the Age of Reason,", undated. (Folder 32: 15)
  - "Equality: The Greek Experience,", undated. (Folder 32: 16)
    Holograph fragment
  - "Equality: Medieval Christianity and the Reformation,", undated. (Folder 32: 17)
  - "Equality in the Medieval Period,", undated. (Folder 32: 18)
  - "Equality in the New Testament,", undated. (Folder 32: 19)
  - "Equality in the Old Testament,", undated. (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - "Equality I,", undated. (Folder 33: 2)
  - "Equality: The Reformation Left,", undated. (Folder 33: 3)
  - "Europe on the Eve of World War I,", undated. (Folder 33: 4)
    Holograph. Includes printed matter about Henry Adams
  - "Extra Systemic Impulses to Equality in the Middle Ages: Warfare, the Market, Women and Heretics,", undated. (Folder 33: 5)
  - "Faculty Responsibility for the Mess in Higher Education,", undated. (Folder 33: 6)
  - "Fashions in Ideas: Economic Theory and the Climate of Opinion,", undated. (Folder 33: 7)
  - "Ferdinand Tönnies, 1855-1936,", undated. (Folder 33: 8)
  - "Feudalism Revolution and Neo-Feudalism,", undated. (Folder 33: 9)
  - "The Formative Images of the Garden,", undated. (Folder 33: 10)
  - "France and the Onset of Decadence,", undated. (Folder 33: 11)
  - "Freedom and Crisis in Historiography,", undated. (Folder 33: 12)
  - "The French Revolution,", undated. (Folder 33: 13)
  - "From Emancipation to Conformity,", undated. (Folder 33: 14)
  - "From Prometheus to Oedipus: The Transformation of the Conception of the Hero in the Nineteenth Century,", undated. (Folder 33: 15)
  - Frontier thesis, undated. (Folder 33: 16)
  - "The Future of Higher Education in America,", undated. (Folder 33: 17)
  - "The Future of ROTC at the University of Michigan,", undated. (Folder 33: 18)
    Holograph. Includes a special issue of University Record, 1969 September 22
  - "George Sorel (1847-1922),", undated. (Folder 33: 19)
    Holograph. Includes a printed copy of an article about him
  - "The Golden Bough or the Power of a Wrong Idea,", undated. (Folder 33: 20)
  - "Government and Education: A Test Case for the Role of Government in Society,", undated. (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - "The Growth of the State Science and Technology,", undated. (Folder 34: 2)
  - "Henry Adams (1838-1918),", undated. (Folder 34: 3)
  - "The Historical Morphology of Ernst von Lasaulx,", undated. (Folder 34: 4)
  - "The Historical Novel,", undated. (Folder 34: 5)
    Holograph. Includes holograph bibliography and clippings
  - "Historical Theology and Catholic Ecumenism,", undated. (Folder 34: 6)
    Typescript. Includes holograph notes and a letter from Paul R. Dekar, 1973 July 10
  - "History and Historicism: Conservative or Revolutionary,", undated. (Folder 34: 7)
    Holograph. Includes note and outline
  - "History and the Philosopher: A Study of John Dewey and Reinhold Niebuhr,", undated. (Folder 34: 8)
  - "History or Histories,", undated. (Folder 34: 9)
  - "Hölderlin and the Modern Sensibility,", undated. (Folder 34: 10)
  - "Iconography,", undated. (Folder 34: 11)
  - "The Iconography of Disorder: The Ruined Garden and the Devastated City,", undated. (Folder 34: 12)
  - "The Idea of a Catholic University,", undated. (Folder 34: 13)
  - "Ideological Generation,", undated. (Folder 34: 14)
    Holograph outline and notes and a copy of the British Journal of Sociology, 1977 December
  - "The Image of Science and Technology in Utopian and Science Fiction Literature,", undated. (Folder 34: 15)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes notes and printed matter
  - "Impact of World War I,", undated. (Folder 34: 16)
    Holograph notes. Includes outline and clippings
  - "Imperialism and Decadence,", undated. (Folder 34: 17)
  - "The Inevitability of Tradition,", undated. (Folder 34: 18)
  - "The Intellectual Life of the 1920s,", undated. (Folder 34: 19)
    Holograph. Includes outline
  - "Intellectual Virtue Moral Virtue,", undated. (Folder 34: 20)
  - "Introduction I,", undated. (Folder 34: 21)
  - Introductory remarks, "Contemporary Religious Movements in Central Europe," University of Michigan, undated. (Folder 34: 22)
    Holograph. Includes program
  - "Introibo ad Altare Dei,", undated. (Folder 34: 23)
  - "Is it Possible to be both a Radical Christian and a Political and Culture Conservative?", undated. (Folder 34: 24)
  - "Jacob Burckhardt (1818-1897),", undated. (Folder 34: 25)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes outline and clipping
  - James Fenimore Cooper (1789-1851), undated. (Folder 34: 26)
  - Johann Joachim Winckelmann (1717-1768), undated. (Folder 34: 27)
    Holograph. Includes outline and typescript list of references
  - Lecture notes, History 460  Nineteenth Century European Intellectual, undated. (Folder 34: 28)
  - "Leninism  Marxian Irrationalism,", undated. (Folder 34: 29)
    Holograph notes
  - "Liberal Education: Is it a Matter of Courses or Questions?", undated. (Folder 34: 30)
    Typescript. Includes a letter from Kenneth L. Deutsch, 1989 March 23
  - "Liberty, Freedom and the Catholic Church,", undated. (Folder 34: 31)
    Holograph. Includes an issue of Commonweal, 1963 June 21
  - "Lord Acton,", undated. (Folder 34: 32)
  - Lord Acton (John Emerich Edward First Baron) 1834-1902,", undated. (Folder 34: 33)
    Holograph. Includes notes
  - Lord Acton and the American Quest for Liberty,", undated. (Folder 34: 34)
  - "Lord Acton and the United States,", undated. (Folder 34: 35)
  - "Lord Acton's Name: The Debatable Land,", undated. (Folder 34: 36)
  - "The Loss of Limits and the Retreat from Responsibility," review of Allen J. Matuson, Unraveling of America: A History of Liberalism in the 1960s, undated. (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - "Luxury II,", undated. (Folder 35: 2)
  - "Luxury III,", undated. (Folder 35: 3)
  - "Marx-Engels and Equality in Primitive Society,", undated. (Folder 35: 4)
  - "Marxism and Modernity,", undated. (Folder 35: 5)
  - "Max Nordau and Degeneration,", undated. (Folder 35: 6)
  - "The Medieval Model of Social Reconstruction and the Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Reality,", undated. (Folder 35: 7)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a letter to Franz H. Mueller, 1981 July 21, and printed matter
  - "The Modern in Literature," series of reviews, undated. (Folder 35: 8)
  - "Modernity and the Transformation of the Garden,", undated. (Folder 35: 9)
  - "Moral Clarity in the Nuclear Age: A Letter of Catholic Clergy and Laity," by Stephen Tonsor,(?), undated. (Folder 35: 10)
  - "Myth, History and the Problem of Desacralized Time,", undated. (Folder 35: 11)
  - "Nationalism,", undated. (Folder 35: 12)
    Holograph notes and outline. Includes printed matter
  - "Naturalism in Literature,", undated. (Folder 35: 13)
  - "The New Natural Law and the Problem of Equality,", undated. (Folder 35: 14)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes notes and related materials
  - "The Nineteenth Century Revival of Myth,", undated. (Folder 35: 15)
  - "The Not so Strange Death of the Whig Interpretation of History,", undated. (Folder 35: 16)
  - "On Living at the End of an Era,", undated. (Folder 35: 17)
    Holograph. Includes clipping
  - "Order and Degree: The Medieval Quest for Individuality within the Bounds of Community,", undated. (Folder 35: 18)
  - "Order and History,", undated. (Folder 35: 19)
    Holograph. Includes printed copy of an article by Carl G. Hempel
  - "Oswald Spengler and the Decline of the West,", undated. (Folder 35: 20)
  - Panel discussion about Dilemmas of Christian Social Intervention,", undated. (Folder 35: 21)
  - "The Perception of Decadence,", undated. (Box-folder 36: 1)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes poems, clipping, and notes
  - "Philosophical, Political and Religious Elements in the Invention of Decadence,", undated. (Folder 36: 2)
  - "Plato and Equality,", undated. (Folder 36: 3)
  - Poems, undated. (Folder 36: 4)
  - "Poetry and Revolution," Modern Age, 1968-69 Winter (Folder 36: 5)
    Printed copy
  - "Positive Elements in Liberal Protestantism," and "Albrecht Ritschl (1822-1889),", undated. (Folder 36: 6)
    Holograph. Includes outline and notes
  - "Power, Authority and University Administration,", undated. (Folder 36: 7)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a confidential report, 1971 January 12
  - "The Practical Consequences of the Darwinian Revolution,", undated. (Folder 36: 8)
  - "The Problem of Universal History,", undated. (Folder 36: 9)
  - Proposal for a Graduate Program in Religion, undated. (Folder 36: 10)
  - "The Psychedelic Schoolmaster," review of Sybille Bedford's Aldous Huxley: A Biography, undated. (Folder 36: 11)
  - "Quest for Liberty: America in Acton's Thought," The Acton Institute, undated. (Folder 36: 12)
    Printed copy. Includes letter, notes, and printed materials
  - "Race and Theories of Decadence,", undated. (Folder 36: 13)
  - "The Radical Critique of Equality and Democracy,", undated. (Folder 36: 14)
  - "The Reconstruction of Political Theory,", undated. (Folder 36: 15)
  - "Religion as an Historical Factor in the Eighteenth Century,", undated. (Folder 36: 16)
  - "Religion in Contemporary Politics,", undated. (Folder 36: 17)
  - "The Renaissance Sense of the Past,", undated. (Folder 36: 18)
    Holograph. Includes related notes and typescript article
  - A Response to A. M. C. Waterman, "Christian Political Economy: Malthus to Margaret Thatcher,", undated. (Folder 36: 19)
  - "The Restoration of American Politics,", undated. (Folder 36: 20)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a letter of commendation
  - "Restoration Conservatism,", undated. (Folder 36: 21)
  - Review of Alexis de Tocqueville, Democracy in America, The Henry Reeve text revised by Francis Bowen, 1966, undated. (Folder 36: 22)
  - Review of "Catholics and the Market Economy," Modern Age, 1959-60 Winter (Folder 36: 23)
  - Review of Christopher Weber, Aufklärung und Orthodoxie am Mittelrhein, 1820-1850, undated. (Folder 36: 24)
    Holograph, typescript, and printed copy
  - Review of David W. Morgan, The Socialist Left and the German Revolution: A History of the German Independent Social Democratic Party, 1917-1922, The Historian, undated. (Folder 36: 25)
  - Review of Friedrich Georg Jünger's classic, The Perfection of Technology, undated. (Folder 36: 26)
  - Review of Gerhard Valerius, Deutscher Katholozismus und Lamennais. Die Auseinanderseizung in der Katbolischen Publizistik, 1817-1854, undated. (Box-folder 37: 1)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - Review of Gertrude Himmelfarb, On Liberty and Liberalism: The Case of John Stuart Mill, undated. (Folder 37: 2)
  - Review of Jacob Burckhardt, Tradition and the Crisis of Western Culture, undated. (Folder 37: 3)
  - Review of Joris-Karl Huysmus, A'Rebours (Against the Grain) Against Nature, undated. (Folder 37: 4)
    Includes holograph and typescript fragments, undated, and an article by Carol Rosenberg, 1968 April 20
  - Review of Julius Dorneich's Franz Josef Buss und die Katholische Bewegung in Baden, undated. (Folder 37: 5)
  - Review of Klaus Epstein, "The Genesis of German Conservatism,", undated. (Folder 37: 6)
  - Review of Klaus Epstein's article, "Friedrich Meinecke, Ausgewählter Briefwechsel," History and Theory, 1964, undated. (Folder 37: 7)
  - Review of Kurt J. Borkman, Kenelm Digby's Broad Stone of Humor: the Chivalric Vision in Pre-Victorian England, undated. (Folder 37: 8)
  - Review of Lord Acton (John Emerich Edward First Baron), 1834-1902, undated. (Folder 37: 9)
  - Review of Max Weber's The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism, undated. (Folder 37: 10)
    Holograph. Includes related holograph fragment and printed matter
  - Review of "The Origins of Beard's Economic Interpretation of the Constitution," Journal of the History of Ideas, undated. (Folder 37: 11)
  - Review of a paper by Mr. Morse, undated. (Folder 37: 12)
  - Review of Philip Mason, Kipling: The Glass, The Shadow and the Fire, undated. (Folder 37: 13)
  - Review of a proposal from Emory University to the National Endowment for the Humanities for a Summer Institute on "Giambattista Vico and Humanistic Knowledge, 1991-1992, undated. (Folder 37: 14)
    Includes related material
  - Review of Published Essays, 1966-1985: Collected Works of Eric Voegelin, Volume 12, Louisiana State University Press, undated. (Folder 37: 15)
  - Review of Réne Rémond, The High Wind in France from 1815 to de Gaulle, undated. (Folder 37: 16)
  - Review of Whittaker Chambers' Cold Friday, undated. (Folder 37: 17)
  - "Revisionism,", undated. (Folder 37: 18)
  - "The Role of Creative Minorities in Periods of Cultural Crisis,", undated. (Folder 37: 19)
  - "Rousseau and Equality,", undated. (Folder 37: 20)
  - "Second Thoughts: Forty Years Later, The Liberal Critique of Presidential Power,", undated. (Folder 37: 21)
    Typescript draft. Includes printed matter
  - "The Shift in Christianity and the Invention of Decadence,", undated. (Folder 37: 22)
  - "Socialism,", undated. (Folder 37: 23)
  - "Social Science and the Abridgement of Political Choice,", undated. (Folder 37: 24)
  - "Some Reflections on the Accident in History, Personal and Otherwise,", undated. (Folder 37: 25)
  - "South African G. M. Shares,", undated. (Folder 37: 26)
  - Speech about Henry Regnery, undated. (Folder 37: 27)
  - "The Star Factories,", undated. (Folder 37: 28)
  - "Star Wars on Campus: The University and Defense of a Free Society,", undated. (Folder 37: 29)
  - "Student Autonomy and Financial Independence in Education Beyond the Secondary Level,", undated. (Folder 37: 30)
  - "The Student Revolt: Who has Failed?", undated. (Folder 37: 31)
  - "The Surprise," poem, undated. (Folder 37: 32)
  - "Symbolism,", undated. (Folder 37: 33)
    Holograph lecture notes and related matters
  - "Thomas Hobbes and the Ideas of Primitive Society and Natural Equality,", undated. (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - "Time Eternity and the College Campus,", undated. (Folder 38: 2)
  - "Totalitarian Democracy,", undated. (Folder 38: 3)
    Holograph. Includes fragment of an article and printed matter
  - "The Tragedy of Munich,", undated. (Folder 38: 4)
    Holograph. Includes related clippings
  - "A Trip to the City Dump," review of Brian F. Griffin's Panic among the Philistines, undated. (Folder 38: 5)
  - "Two Cheers for Behemoth University,", undated. (Folder 38: 6)
  - "Überstudiert" in Chicago, undated. (Folder 38: 7)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes an issue of The New Republic, 1988 April
  - "The Uses of the Past,", undated. (Folder 38: 8)
  - "The View from the London Bridge,", undated. (Folder 38: 9)
  - "Weimar Germany and the Nazi Seizure of Power,", undated. (Folder 38: 10)
    Holograph. Includes typescript fragment and clipping
  - "Western Intellectuals and Marxist Utopias,", undated. (Folder 38: 11)
    Clippings
  - "What a Liberal Arts Education cannot Teach You,", undated. (Folder 38: 12)
    Holograph. Includes clippings
  - "What did the Liberals Want?", undated. (Folder 38: 13)
  - "What Is Christian Education all About?", undated. (Folder 38: 14)
  - "What Is the Purpose of Politics?", undated. (Folder 38: 15)
  - "What Is there Left to be Romantic About?", undated. (Folder 38: 16)
  - "What to do while Awaiting the Apocalypse: The Role of Creative Minorities in a Time of Cultural Crises,", undated. (Folder 38: 17)
  - "When Luxury Became Decadence: The Luxury Debate of Late Eighteenth Century,", undated. (Folder 38: 18)
  - "Where the Wasteland Begins,", undated. (Folder 38: 19)
  - "Who Killed the Liberal Arts,?", undated. (Folder 38: 20)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes an announcement
  - "Who Should Pay the Cost of Post Secondary Education?", undated. (Folder 38: 21)
  - "Why I am a Republican and a Conservative,", undated. (Folder 38: 22)
  - "Why I am not a Neo-Conservative,", undated. (Folder 38: 23)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes letters to the editor, National Review, 1986
  - "Why the United States Is still a Revolutionary Society,", undated. (Folder 38: 24)
    Holograph. Includes a letter from Billy Ray Cox
  - "The Wintry Breath of Evolution,", undated. (Folder 38: 25)
  - "World War II: The Unexpected in History,", undated. (Folder 38: 26)
  - Review of Stefan Losch, Döllinger und Frankreich: Eine Geistige Allianz, 1823-1871, 1958 January. (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - "Pacifism," Chicago Sunday Tribune Magazine, 1962 February 25. (Folder 39: 2)
  - "The New Left: Fellowship of Bleeding Hearts," Michigan Daily Magazine, 1966 November 17. (Folder 39: 3)
    Printed copy; "The New Left," undated. Holograph. Includes an article, "Nirvana Now," Daniel Moynihan, American Scholar, 1967 Autumn. Printed copy
  - "On Living at the End of an Era," speech, annual meeting of the Philadelphia Society, Chicago, 1968. (Folder 39: 4)
  - "Foundations and the Public Interest,", circa 1969. (Folder 39: 5)
  - "Nihilism and the Intellectual Crisis of our Time," outline and lecture for 1969 Eastern/Southern Summer School (Folder 39: 6)
  - "Alienation and Relevance in Higher Education, National Association of Manufacturers (NAM) Education Committee meeting, Washington, D.C., 1969 April 1-2. (Folder 39: 7)
    Holograph, undated. Includes a printed copy, Dateline, 1969 June and a typescript copy, undated. Also includes an article, "Are you Listening? undated; a letter to Richard Nixon, 1969 May 1; related correspondence, note, and other materials
  - "Commentary: Who Should Decide Who Goes to College?" General Session IV, 25th National Conference on Higher Education, American Association for Higher Education, Chicago, 1970 March 3. (Folder 39: 8)
  - "The Role of the Professor," Alumni News, 1970 April. (Folder 39: 9)
  - "Campus Turmoil  Who's Really at Fault?" Sunday News, 1970 May 31. (Folder 39: 10)
  - "The Church-Related College: Special Mission on Educational Anachronism?" Liberal Education, 1970 October. (Folder 39: 11)
    Printed copy. Includes holograph and typescript copies and related correspondence
  - "Who Should Pay the Cost of Post Secondary Education?" address, National Meeting of College Entrance Exam Board, New York City, 1970. (Folder 39: 12)
  - "Book Publishing: How it Looks to a Personal Publisher,", 1971 January 7. (Folder 39: 13)
  - "Faculty Diversity and University Survival," address, group of Cornell representatives, New York City, 1971 January 21. (Folder 39: 14)
    Typescript. Includes a note from William F. Buckley, Jr., 1972 January 6
  - "Science and Technology and the Cultural Revolution," dinner speech, Tau Beta Phi Engineering Honorary Society, University of Michigan, 1971 April 2. (Folder 39: 15)
    Also delivered as a lecture, Illinois State University Festival of Contemporary Arts, Illinois, 1971 May. Holograph. Includes notes
  - "Some Observations," New Departures in Western Political Thought," the School of Eric Voegelin, symposium, University of Notre Dame, 1971 April 29-30. (Folder 39: 16)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes holograph fragment and program
  - "A Fresh Start: American History and Political Order,", 1971 July. (Folder 39: 17)
    Holograph and typescript copies and related materials
  - "The Iconography of Disorder: The Ruined Garden and the Devastated City,", 1971 August. (Folder 39: 18)
  - "Modernity, Science and Rationality,", 1971 August. (Folder 39: 19)
  - "The Poet against Machine,", 1971 September. (Folder 39: 20)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes printed copy of an article by Christine Avery, 1964
  - Plans for bicentennial celebrations of American independence, 1971 November 26. (Folder 39: 21)
  - "Modernity, Science and Rationality," Modern Age, 1972 Spring. (Folder 39: 22)
    Printed copy. Includes related materials
  - "Redefining Liberal Education," Modern Age, 1972 Summer. (Folder 39: 23)
    Printed copy and holograph. Includes related materials
  - Panelist, "A Papal Biography: Techniques and Problems, American Historical Association Session 70, 1972 December 29. (Folder 39: 24)
    Typescript. Includes a note
  - "Tradition and Reform in Education,", circa 1973. (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - "Business and the Counter-Culture, National Association of Manufacturers (NAM) Education Committee, 1973 October 18. (Folder 40: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1974 March 14. (Folder 40: 3)
  - Hoover as Secretary of Commerce, 1921-1928" and "Hoover and the Presidency, 1929-1933," seminar, 1974 April 25-27, and August 7-9. (Folder 40: 4)
    Includes one untitled holograph paper and related correspondence
  - "Political Idealism and Political Reality," Modern Age, 1974 Fall. (Folder 40: 5)
    Printed copy. Includes holograph and typescript
  - "Conservative Catholicism," remarks, Seminar on Liberal Catholicism and Conservative Catholicism in Nineteenth Century Europe," American Catholic Historical Association, Boston College, Massachusetts, 1975 April 4-5. (Folder 40: 6)
    Holograph. Includes related correspondence
  - "The Conservative Origins of Collectivism," Law and Liberty Conference, San Francisco, California, 1976 January 14-18. (Folder 40: 7)
  - Remarks, Philadelphia Society, 1976 April 9. (Folder 40: 8)
    Holograph. Includes a typescript article by Richard Whalen, 1976 April 9, and clippings
  - Review of Friedrich Engel-Janosi, Die Wahrheit der Geschichte. Versuche zur Geschichtsschreibung in der Neuzeit, Catholic Historical Review, 1977 April. (Folder 40: 9)
    Printed copy. Includes typescript copy
  - "The Impact of the Academy in the Formation of Opinion: Some Second Thoughts," Imprints, 1977 September. (Folder 40: 10)